<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on nathan adan</title>
    <link>https://nate.unpass.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on nathan adan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>copyright © 2022, nathan adan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 01:39:27 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nate.unpass.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a humbling week</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/a-humbling-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 01:39:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/a-humbling-week/</guid>
      <description>A busy and humbling week and a half. Let&amp;rsquo;s get accomplishments out of the way:
 Replaced the default NGINX 404 page (try it out!) Continued work on the Linode playbook  Added CertBot tasks Replaced some copy tasks with synchronize/rsync ones for efficiency   Continued setting up CloudFlare Load Balancing  Added the Linode instance&amp;rsquo;s IP in the failover pool    Now for the humbling part. Lessons learned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>failover and over</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/failover-and-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 04:26:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/failover-and-over/</guid>
      <description>hello again! I noticed that CloudFlare has this option for load balancing and thought, &amp;ldquo;Why not use it?&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending the past week learning how I can quickly deploy cloud instances for the blog as backup. Ansible has been a great friend for this. Being already familiar with docker-compose yamls, I was able to step into playbooks with a fair amount of confidence. As of writing, the playbook can set up the site, but I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out how to automate SSL certificates to make CF happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cloudflare and ssh galore</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/cloudflare-and-ssh-galore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 15:10:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/cloudflare-and-ssh-galore/</guid>
      <description>Just migrated all of the blog&amp;rsquo;s DNS records over from Google to CloudFlare and I gotta say, I&amp;rsquo;m really impressed.
For starters, the less power Google has over me, the better. Plus I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s worth using their &amp;ldquo;domains&amp;rdquo; services outside of the name lease as it&amp;rsquo;s quite featureless. I&amp;rsquo;m not a paid shill for CF but there are so many useful features on the free tier alone
 Wayback archiving Basic bot/DDOS protection (I&amp;rsquo;d add a rate limiting method on top of this) Location-based firewall rules Catch-all email addresses for dropping unwanted spam Analytics that don&amp;rsquo;t rely on Google  The only bump along the way was getting LetsEncrypt and CF&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;full (strict)&amp;rdquo; SSL/TLS mode to get along with each other, but that&amp;rsquo;s what certbot --nginx is for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 14:53:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/about/</guid>
      <description>hey, i&amp;rsquo;m nate. I&amp;rsquo;m 22, in L1 support, and am an aspiring sysadmin.
I grew up fascinated with computers at an early age. In &amp;lsquo;03, my parents got me a Gateway desktop and filled it to the brim with CD-ROM &amp;amp; Shockwave games. A couple of decades, certs, and a degree later, I&amp;rsquo;ve been blessed with the title &amp;ldquo;Family Tech Support&amp;rdquo; (and cursed with a -3/-4 prescription).
While not the most extroverted person I try to be the most insightful, and am huge on fine details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 14:08:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/links/</guid>
      <description>work  resume linkedin indeed github (wip)  personal  car stuff soundcloud bandcamp (inactive)  contact  hello@unpass.net discord: nate#6000  thanks for stopping by! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>finally</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 15:44:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/finally/</guid>
      <description>the site is finally live! Notes to self
 Port forward 80/443 Ensure &amp;ldquo;include /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/*;&amp;rdquo; is in nginx.conf. Certbot is very picky about filenames  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a checklist</title>
      <link>https://nate.unpass.net/a-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:47:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nate.unpass.net/a-checklist/</guid>
      <description>(updated 24 Jan, 2023)
Because who needs GitHub&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;issues&amp;rdquo;
docker mc server  Documentation in GitHub docker-compose.yml in a repo Get RCON console to listen to game chat  hugo-blackbear  Replace nate.unpass.net pages with an example site In readme.md: how to set up custom nav links (add blog post)  nate.unpass.net  Add subscribe/rss to /links Use cloud provider for active-passive load balancing (Linode? AWS?)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
